<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teaching and Outreach | Benjamin Davidson</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/teaching_and_outreach/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/teaching_and_outreach/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Teaching and Outreach</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:1313/media/icon_hu3010647768737102974.png</url>
      <title>Teaching and Outreach</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/teaching_and_outreach/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delta Certificate</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/teaching_and_outreach/certificate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/teaching_and_outreach/certificate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In August 2024, Ben completed the requirements for the &lt;em&gt;Delta Certificate in Research, Teaching, and Learning&lt;/em&gt; at the University of Wisconsin-Madison.  The Delta program at UW-Madison fosters growth in teaching, outreach, and mentoring in the context of reasearch.  The certificate is based on several seminar courses and culminates in a final project where evidence-based practices are implemented in a classroom setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;delta-courses&#34;&gt;Delta Courses&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research Mentor Training&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emerging Technologies and Accelerating Change: Preparing for tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s college classroom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improv to Improve Science Communication and Teaching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workshop in Educational Leadership and Policy Analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-project&#34;&gt;Final Project&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/teaching_and_outreach/delta/&#34;&gt;For the final project&lt;/a&gt;, Ben developed an outreach activity for local high school students to learn about plastic ocean pollution through a hands on coding activity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Undergraduate Mentoring</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/teaching_and_outreach/mentoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/teaching_and_outreach/mentoring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Across several of my research proejcts, I have had the opportunity to involve undergraduate students in my work.  This involvement has allowed me to provide a critical learning experience for students interested in research.  Additionally, I have completed research mentor training as part of my &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/teaching_and_outreach/certificate/&#34;&gt;Delta Certificate in Teaching, Learning and Research,&lt;/a&gt; further enhancing my ability to support and guide these students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;microplastics-on-beaches-in-lake-superior&#34;&gt;Microplastics on Beaches in Lake Superior&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kallyn Batista&lt;/strong&gt; (Spring/Summer 2021): Kallyn assisted with setting up and conducting field experiments to collect sand samples from Lake Superior.  Additionally, Kallyn played a significant role in performing the microplastic separation procedures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sabeel Samrah&lt;/strong&gt; (Fall 2021 - Summer 2022): Sabeel assisted in identifying and counting microplastic particles from processed samples. Additionally, Sabeel processed raw beach sand and analyzed the sediment characteristics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achievements:&lt;/strong&gt; Kallyn and Sabeel both presented in the campus undergraduate research symposium.  This research project, including the contributions of both Kallyn and Sabeel, was &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/publication/1-davidson-microplastic-2022&#34;&gt;published in 2022&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;marine-debris-modeling-and-experiments&#34;&gt;Marine Debris Modeling and Experiments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jamie Brenner&lt;/strong&gt; (Fall 2022 - Summer 2023): Jamie contributed to developing the 1D and 2D swash zone models for buoyant marine debris and further assisted with laboratory experiments at Queen&amp;rsquo;s University&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ethan Steichen&lt;/strong&gt; (Summer 2024): Ethan assisted with the laboratory experiments at Queen&amp;rsquo;s University.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achievements:&lt;/strong&gt; Jamie presented a poster on the 2D beaching model at the 2023 Young Coastal Scientists and Engineers Conference - Americas.  Additionally, the 1D swash zone marine debris model was  &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/publication/2-davidson-beaching-2023&#34;&gt;published in 2023&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- Marine Debris Fragmentation --&gt;
&lt;!-- Evan Pittam (Summer/Gall 2024) --&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mathematical Modeling Outreach with MEHS Students</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/teaching_and_outreach/delta/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/teaching_and_outreach/delta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In April 2024, Ben developed and hosted an outreach event between the Fluid Mechanics in Environmental Processes (FMEP) Group at UW-Madison and a group of high school students from Madison East High School (MEHS).  The event was focused around a live coding activity where students learned how to mathematically model plastic pollution on beaches using MATLAB.  The code files and original handout are &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/davidson-ben/mathematical_modeling_outreach_2023&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;available on github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developing and leading this outreach event was the final project for the Delta Certificate in Research, Teaching, and Learning.  Over the course of the semester, Ben worked on developing a literature informed activity to engage diverse students in learning to code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication Fellowship</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/teaching_and_outreach/fab-fellow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/teaching_and_outreach/fab-fellow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ben began the Fabrication Fellowship at the University of Wisconsin-Madison Design &amp;amp; Innovation (D&amp;amp;I) Lab in August 2023.  The D&amp;amp;I Lab is a campus makerspace equiped with a variety of design and prototyping tools.  As a Fabrication Fellow, Ben served as a student shop manager, overseeing undergraduate staff members and assisting users with their projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ben oversaw all 3D printing activities in the lab.  The D&amp;amp;I Lab houses over 30 3D printers (FDM, SLA, and SLS) and produces over 2,000 individual prints for campus users each semester.  In managing the 3D printing area, Ben organized student workers to maintain printers, assist users, stock materials, and ensure the smooth operation of the space.  Ben also played a key role in transitioning the fleet of printers to next-generation models, optimizing the user experience, and helping to oversee the development of an automatic print queue system.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grandparents University</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/teaching_and_outreach/gpu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/teaching_and_outreach/gpu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Each summer we join the Wisconsin Sea Grant in leading a session for &lt;a href=&#34;https://uwalumni.com/grandparents-university/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Grandparents University&lt;/a&gt; at the University of Wisconsin-Madison.  Through this program, we host elementary and middle school aged students with their grandparents in our lab to explore the topics of waves and microplasitc pollution.  Ben has led the lab tour and wave demonstrations in the summers of 2022 and 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be joining with the Wisconsin Sea Grant again in the summer of 2025 to lead demonstations in the Water Science and Engineering Laboratory wave flume for Grandparents University.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEE 310: Introductory Fluid Mechanics</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/teaching_and_outreach/cee-310/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/teaching_and_outreach/cee-310/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Fall 2021 and Fall 2022, Ben served as a Teaching Assistant for the Civil &amp;amp; Environemntal Engineering course, &lt;em&gt;CEE 310: Introductory Fluid Mechanics&lt;/em&gt;.  Throughout the semester, Ben led weekly discussions to reinforce lecture material and supervised hands-on laboratory experiments.  These experiments provided students with practical experience, allowing them to apply the fluid mechanics pricipals they studied in lecures in a hands-on environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
