<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Benjamin Davidson</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Benjamin Davidson</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:1313/media/icon_hu3010647768737102974.png</url>
      <title>Benjamin Davidson</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Particles</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/project/particles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/project/particles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For experiments concerning plastic particle beaching, I have created a wide range of plastic particles in different sizes, shapes, and types. For various materials and particle characteristics, I have used various fabrication techniques, each of which offers distinct advantages and disadvantages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;tools-used&#34;&gt;Tools used&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CNC Router&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Waterjet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lasercutter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FMD &amp;amp; SLA 3D Printers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various hand tools for finishing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weston Roundtable Lecture Series: Speaker Benjamin Davidson</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/weston/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/weston/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ben presented the Weston Roundtable lecture on October 24, 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mediaspace.wisc.edu/media/WestonRoundtable_BenDavidson_20241024/1_ycdszaun&#34;&gt; Weston Roundtable Lecture Series Video Archive &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arduino Camera Trigger</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/project/arduino-trigger/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/project/arduino-trigger/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Page Under Construction: photo coming soon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I designed and built a system to synchronize and trigger cameras for experiments in the Queen&amp;rsquo;s University large wave basin. The system is centered around an Arduino, which receives a start trigger from the wave paddle, waits for a specified duration, and then produces a square wave at a specified frequency via a power supply and relay. This output signal triggers the cameras for image capture. Additionally, the trigger system uses LED indicators to show the system status and is housed within a 3D-printed enclosure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also created an adapted version for use at the University of Wisconsin-Madison&amp;rsquo;s Water Science and Engineering Laboratory wave flume. In addition to triggering the cameras, this version also synchronized the image capture with a data acquisition system, which captured wave height data from ultrasonic wave gauges and velocity data from Vectrino ADVs and ADV Profilers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;tools-used&#34;&gt;Tools used&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arduino Uno and various components&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soldered components for final assembly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FMD 3D printing for enclosure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Madison East High School Outreach Project</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/madison-east-high-school-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/madison-east-high-school-group/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ben organized an day of science outreach for local high school students focused around a mathematical modeling live coding activity.  Read more about this outreach event &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/teaching_and_outreach/delta/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transatlantic Research Partnership - Casimir Study</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/france/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/france/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ben spent a month collaborating with researchers at IRPHE in Marseille, France to set up preliminary experiemnts to study the Casimir effect on buoyant marine debris in surface wave turbulence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education and Research</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/education_and_research/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/education_and_research/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beaching model for buoyant marine debris in bore-driven swash</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/publication/2-davidson-beaching-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/publication/2-davidson-beaching-2023/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication Fellowship</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/teaching_and_outreach/fab-fellow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/teaching_and_outreach/fab-fellow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ben began the Fabrication Fellowship at the University of Wisconsin-Madison Design &amp;amp; Innovation (D&amp;amp;I) Lab in August 2023.  The D&amp;amp;I Lab is a campus makerspace equiped with a variety of design and prototyping tools.  As a Fabrication Fellow, Ben served as a student shop manager, overseeing undergraduate staff members and assisting users with their projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ben oversaw all 3D printing activities in the lab.  The D&amp;amp;I Lab houses over 30 3D printers (FDM, SLA, and SLS) and produces over 2,000 individual prints for campus users each semester.  In managing the 3D printing area, Ben organized student workers to maintain printers, assist users, stock materials, and ensure the smooth operation of the space.  Ben also played a key role in transitioning the fleet of printers to next-generation models, optimizing the user experience, and helping to oversee the development of an automatic print queue system.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Young Coastal Scientist and Engineers Conference - Americas (YCSEC-A)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/ycseca/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/ycseca/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The University of Wisconsin - Madison hosted the 9th Young Coastal Scientists and Engineers Conference – Americas (YCSEC-A).  Ben served on the student organization committee, helping to faciliate a smooth conference experience for the attendees.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mathematical Modeling Outreach with MEHS Students</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/teaching_and_outreach/delta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/teaching_and_outreach/delta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In April 2024, Ben developed and hosted an outreach event between the Fluid Mechanics in Environmental Processes (FMEP) Group at UW-Madison and a group of high school students from Madison East High School (MEHS).  The event was focused around a live coding activity where students learned how to mathematically model plastic pollution on beaches using MATLAB.  The code files and original handout are &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/davidson-ben/mathematical_modeling_outreach_2023&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;available here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developing and leading this outreach event was the final project for the Delta Certificate in Research, Teaching, and Learning.  Over the course of the semester, Ben worked on developing a literature informed activity to engage diverse students in learning to code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wisconsin Sea Grant &#39;Ask a Scientist&#39;</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/ask-a-scientist/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/ask-a-scientist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ben presented a virtual lesson to high school students at Rhinelander High School about microplastics in the Great Lakes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microplastic contamination of sediments across and within three beaches in western Lake Superior</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/publication/1-davidson-microplastic-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/publication/1-davidson-microplastic-2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEE 310: Introductory Fluid Mechanics</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/teaching_and_outreach/cee-310/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/teaching_and_outreach/cee-310/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Fall 2021 and Fall 2022, Ben served as a Teaching Assistant for the Civil &amp;amp; Environemntal Engineering course, &lt;em&gt;CEE 310: Introductory Fluid Mechanics&lt;/em&gt;.  Throughout the semester, Ben led weekly discussions to reinforce lecture material and supervised hands-on laboratory experiments.  These experiments provided students with practical experience, allowing them to apply the fluid mechanics pricipals they studied in lecures in a hands-on environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UW - Madison Day at the Capitol</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/day-at-the-capitol/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/day-at-the-capitol/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ben presented work regarding microplastic pollution and issues to legislators and staff at the Wisconsin state capitol.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wave Flume Beach</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/project/beach/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/project/beach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the fall of 2020, I designed and constructed a beach for the Water Science and Engineering Lab&amp;rsquo;s wave flume at the University of Wisconsin-Madison, intended for microplastic beaching experiments. The beach is built using 80/20 extruded aluminum T-slot frames, secured with a combination of standard and custom fasteners. The surface is made of 1/2&amp;quot; acrylic, attached to the frame and covered with white contact paper to create an opaque surface for imaging. Additionally, I designed a wooden frame to support two cameras above the beach surface for experimental imaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;tools-used&#34;&gt;Tools used&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8020 Framing System&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Miter saw and drill press for custom brackets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Table saw for sizing and chamfering beach toe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Silicone seal for acrylic butt joints&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various hand tools for assembly and finishing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Portfolio</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/design_portfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/design_portfolio/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
