<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Featured News | Benjamin Davidson</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Featured News</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>//localhost:1313/media/icon_hu3010647768737102974.png</url>
      <title>Featured News</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>CoPartCoFlow Summer School in France</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/copartcoflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/copartcoflow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In June 2025, I had the opportunity to participate in the CoPartCoFlow summer school, held in La londe les Maures, France. The week-long program focused on complex particles in complex flows and brought together researchers from across disciplines to explore the behavior, modeling, and measurement of particle-laden flows in environmental settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The format combined lectures from leading scientists, poster sessions, and hands-on components that encouraged collaboration and discussion. Topics ranged from particle dynamics and turbulent transport to modeling approaches and experimental techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of the program, I presented my ongoing research on the flow and transport of debris and contaminants in the swash zone. This work investigates how plastic pollution or solute contamination move throughout the coastal zone, in a highly unsteady and spatially variable environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond the technical content, it was a truly rewarding experience to meet other early-career researchers and engage with experts whose work I have long admired. The conversations and connections formed during the week have already influenced my thinking and opened the door to future collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to the organizers and instructors who made the week so valuable, and to all the participants for fostering such a collegial and stimulating environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Green Lab Certification</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/green-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/green-lab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ben led a year-long initiative by Dr. Pujara&amp;rsquo;s FMEP group in collaboration with the UW-Madison Office of Sustainability to certify the lab through the My Green Lab program.  By the end of the year, the lab earned &lt;strong&gt;Gold Certification,&lt;/strong&gt; recognizing its ongoing commitment to environmental responsibility in research practices and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weston Roundtable Lecture Series: Speaker Benjamin Davidson</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/weston/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/weston/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ben presented the Weston Roundtable lecture on October 24, 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mediaspace.wisc.edu/media/WestonRoundtable_BenDavidson_20241024/1_ycdszaun&#34;&gt; Weston Roundtable Lecture Series Video Archive &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Madison East High School Outreach Project</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/madison-east-high-school-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/madison-east-high-school-group/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ben organized an day of science outreach for local high school students focused around a mathematical modeling live coding activity.  Read more about this outreach event &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/teaching_and_outreach/delta/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transatlantic Research Partnership - Casimir Study</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/france/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/france/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ben spent a month collaborating with researchers at IRPHE in Marseille, France to set up preliminary experiemnts to study the Casimir effect on buoyant marine debris in surface wave turbulence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research in the news</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/boreal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/boreal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Greg Seitz of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.boreal.org/2023/12/13/475686/microplastics-pose-big-problems-for-lake-superiors-beaches&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Boreal Community Media wrote a story&lt;/a&gt; about our &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/publication/1-davidson-microplastic-2022/&#34;&gt;2022 publication&lt;/a&gt; regarding microplasitc pollution on the beaches of Lake Superior.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Young Coastal Scientist and Engineers Conference - Americas (YCSEC-A)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/ycseca/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/ycseca/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The University of Wisconsin - Madison hosted the 9th Young Coastal Scientists and Engineers Conference – Americas (YCSEC-A).  Ben served on the student organization committee, helping to faciliate a smooth conference experience for the attendees.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wisconsin Sea Grant &#39;Ask a Scientist&#39;</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/ask-a-scientist/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/ask-a-scientist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ben presented a virtual lesson to high school students at Rhinelander High School about microplastics in the Great Lakes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UW - Madison Day at the Capitol</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/day-at-the-capitol/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/day-at-the-capitol/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ben presented work regarding microplastic pollution and issues to legislators and staff at the Wisconsin state capitol.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
